Guide to the Merrill G. Burlingame Papers 1880-1990
Montana State University Library, Archives and Special Collections, Manuscript Collections
- Montana and the pioneer west, 3
  - Aviation in Montana* (Box 14, Folder 19)
  - Barbed Wire (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Barberry Bush Properties (Map) (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Barns (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Beads (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Beidler, X. (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - Bicentennial (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - Bicentennial Medal Design, 1976 (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - Big Hole Battlefield (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - Big Timber Woolen Mill (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - Billings Polytechnic (Box 15, Folder 10)
  - Bitterroot (Box 15, Folder 11)
  - Bond, Samuel (Journal) (Box 15, Folder 12)
  - Bonner, Governor John W. Message to the thirty-second Legislative Assembly of the State of Montana (Box 15, Folder 13)
  - Book Reviews (Box 15, Folder 14)
  - Books and Publications (Box 15, Folder 15)
  - Bozeman Trail (Box 15, Folder 16)
  - Bradley, James H. (Box 15, Folder 17)
  - Breweries in Montana (Memorial Fund) (Box 15, Folder 18)
  - Bridger, Jim (Box 15, Folder 19)
  - "British Impressions of Early Rocky Mountain Towns" (Box 15, Folder 20)
  - Broadwater and Company (Box 15, Folder 21)
  - Buffalo (Box 15, Folder 22)
  - Buffalo Jumps* (Box 15, Folder 23)
  - Burlingame and Toole (Box 15, Folder 24)
  - Burlingame, J. (Box 15, Folder 25)
  - Burlington Northern Railroad. M. and J.F. (Box 15, Folder 26)
  - Calfee, White (Box 15, Folder 27)
  - Callaway, L.L. (Box 15, Folder 28)
  - Camels (Box 15, Folder 29)
  - Canada Public Archives (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Canadian Publications (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Carter, Senator Thomas H. (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Cascade and Chouteau County Historic Sites (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - Centennials (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - "Central Montana to 1871," by Clifton Boyd Worthen (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - Chico Hot Springs, Montana (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - Chappel, Harry E. (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - Charbonneau, T. and Sacajawea (Box 16, Folder 9)
  - Cherry Creek Trail (Box 16, Folder 10)
  - Chinese in Montana (Box 16, Folder 11)
  - Church (miscellaneous) (Box 16, Folder 12)
  - Church of England (Box 16, Folder 13)
  - Church (Episcopal) (Box 16, Folder 14)
  - Church (Methodist) (Box 16, Folder 15)
  - Church (Seventh-Day Adventist) (Box 16, Folder 16)
  - "The Cline House in Polson" by Gina Mahugh (Box 16, Folder 17)
  - Coal (Box 16, Folder 18)
  - College of Montana (Deer Lodge)* (Box 16, Folder 19)
  - Communication in Montana, 1866-1911 (Box 16, Folder 20)
  - Communism in Montana (Box 16, Folder 21)
  - Community Development Foundation (Box 16, Folder 22)
  - "Concretions, the Study of Curved Surface Crystallography" (Box 16, Folder 23)
  - Constitution, Montana (Box 16, Folder 24)
  - Contributions of Montana (Box 16, Folder 25)
  - Cook Herd (Box 16, Folder 26)
  - Copper King Mansion (Box 16, Folder 27)
  - Crow's Nest (Army) - Scout's Lookout (Box 16, Folder 28)
  - Dandelions (Box 16, Folder 29)
  - De Smet Cross (Box 16, Folder 30)
  - Diamond City, Montana (Box 16, Folder 31)
  - Dillon Examiner, 1920 (Box 16, Folder 32)
  - Doane, Gustavus C. - military orders (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - Doane - GAR documents (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - Doane - divorce and obituaries (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - Doane - Society of California Pioneers (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - Doane - Mary Doane papers (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - Doane - Howgate expedition ledger (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - Doane - National Archives inventories (Box 17, Folder 7)
  - Doane - Genealogy (Box 17, Folder 8)
  - Doane - Biography draft, Exploration of the Upper Yellowstone (Box 17, Folder 9)
  - Doane - Biography draft, On the way to Yellowstone (Box 17, Folder 10)
  - Doane - Biography draft, From Gardiner to Mount Washburn (Box 17, Folder 11)
  - Doane - Biography draft, Hot Springs along the Yellowstone River (Box 17, Folder 12)
  - Doane - Biography draft, At the Grand Canyon (Box 17, Folder 13)
  - Doane - Biography draft, Around Yellowstone Lake (Box 17, Folder 14)
  - Doane - Biography draft, In search of Truman Everts (Box 17, Folder 15)
  - Doane - Biography draft, In the Geyser Basin (Box 17, Folder 16)
  - Doane - Biography draft, The road home (Box 17, Folder 17)
  - Doane - Secretary of War report, 1875 (Box 17, Folder 18)
  - Doane - edited 1876 journal (Box 17, Folder 19)
  - Doane - edited 1876 journal (Box 17, Folder 20)
  - Doane - Biography notes (Box 17, Folder 21)
  - Doane - Howgate expedition transcript (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - Doane - 1870 Yellowstone report (working copy) (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - Doane - 1870 Yellowstone report (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - Doane - Biography draft, general (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - Doane - Biography draft, general (Box 18, Folder 5)
  - Doane - Biography draft, Chapter 1: Course of Empire (Box 18, Folder 6)
  - Doane - Biography draft, Chapter 2: The Army comes to Montana (Box 18, Folder 7)
  - Doane - Biography draft, Chapter 3: Pursuing the Piegans (Box 18, Folder 8)
  - Doane - Biography draft, Chapter 4: The Discovery of Yellowstone (Box 18, Folder 9)
  - Doane - Biography draft, Chapter 5: Lt. Doane's Report of Discovery
  - Doane - Biography draft, Chapter 6: Through the Park in 1876
  - Doane - Biography draft, Chapter 7: Fostering a National Park (Box 18, Folder 12)
  - Doane - Biography draft, Chapter 8: Life at Fort Ellis (Box 18, Folder 13)
  - Doane - Biography draft, Chapter 9: Developing the Yellowstone Valley (Box 18, Folder 14)
  - Doane - Biography draft, Chapter 10: At the Custer Battlefield (Box 18, Folder 15)
  - Doane - Biography draft, Chapter 11: Marching on the High Plains (Box 18, Folder 16)
  - Doane - Biography draft, Chapter 12: On the trail of the Nez Perce (Box 18, Folder 17)
  - Doane - Biography draft, Chapter 13: From Africa to the Arctic (Box 18, Folder 18)
  - Doane - Biography draft, Chapter 14: Disappearing frontier (Box 18, Folder 19)
  - Doane - Biography draft, Chapter 15: Captain Doane of the 2nd Cavalry (Box 18, Folder 20)
  - Doane - Biography draft, bibliography (Box 18, Folder 21-22)
  - Doane - Biography draft, Research and publishing correspondence (Box 18, Folder 23-25)
  - Doane - Biography draft, Swallow Press correspondence (Box 18, Folder 26)
  - Doane - Biography additional drafts, The Army Comes to Montana (Box 18A, Folder 1)
  - Doane - Biography additional drafts, Indian Affairs in the Judith Basin (Box 18A, Folder 2)
  - Doane - Biography additional drafts, Life at Fort Ellis (Box 18A, Folder 3)
  - Doane - Biography additional drafts, Fostering a National Park (Box 18A, Folder 4)
  - Doane - Biography additional drafts, The Search for a New Crow Reservation (Box 18A, Folder 5)
  - Doane - Bigraphy additional drafts, The Buffalo and the Indian (Box 18A, Folder 6)
  - Doane - Bigraphy additional drafts, At the Custer Battlefield (Box 18A, Folder 7)
  - Doane - Bigraphy additional drafts, First Ponson Experiment (Box 18A, Folder 8)
  - Doane - Bigraphy additional drafts, On the Trial of the Nez Perce (Box 18A, Folder 9)
  - Doane - Bigraphy additional drafts, From Africa to the Arctic (Box 18A, Folder 10)
  - Doane - Bigraphy additional drafts, Disappearing Frontier (Box 18A, Folder 11)
  - Doane - Bigraphy additional drafts, 1876 Journal (Box 18A, Folder 12)
  - Doane - Bigraphy additional drafts, The Army Comes to Montana (Box 18A, Folder 13)
  - Doane - Bigraphy additional drafts, Spring Campaign 1877 (Box 18A, Folder 14)
  - Doane - Bigraphy additional drafts, The Buffalo and the Indian (Box 18A, Folder 15)
  - Doane - Bigraphy additional drafts, segments of Pursuing the Piegans, On the Trail of the Nez Perces, and "Description of the Present Crow Reservation" (Box 18A, Folder 16)
  - Doane - Bigraphy additional drafts, Version III (Box 18A, Folder 17)
  - Doane - Bigraphy additional drafts, Version IV (Box 18A, Folder 18)
  - Dowsing (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - Drannan, William F. (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - Drought sale of cattle, 1934-1936 (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - Drouillard, George (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - "Early American Freighters" by Joseph Hartmann (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - "Early American Freighters" correspondence (Box 19, Folder 6)
  - Early Man (Box 19, Folder 7)
  - Early Montana Men (Box 19, Folder 8)
  - Education in Montana (Box 19, Folder 9)
  - Educational Study (Box 19, Folder 10)
  - Ekalaka, Montana (Box 19, Folder 11)
  - Elections in Montana (Box 19, Folder 12)
  - Elections in Montana (Box 19, Folder 13)
  - Encyclopedia Americana (Box 19, Folder 14)
  - Encyclopedia Britannica (Box 19, Folder 15)
  - "Ethnic Settlement of Montana" H.G. Merriam (Box 19, Folder 16)
  - Extension Department - University of Montana (Box 19, Folder 17)
  - Farmer Labor Party (Box 19, Folder 18)
  - Farming (Box 19, Folder 19)
  - Fergus, James (Box 19, Folder 20)
  - Film and TV Historical Project grant application (Box 19, Folder 21)
  - Finance and Government (Box 19, Folder 22)
  - Fisk Expedition (Box 19, Folder 23)
  - Flags (Box 19, Folder 24)
  - Flag and Seal - Montana (Box 19, Folder 25)
  - Flathead Valley (Upper and Lower) (Box 20, Folder 1)
  - Flour Mills (Box 20, Folder 2)
  - Fort Buford (Box 20, Folder 3)
  - Fort Elizabeth Meagher (Box 20, Folder 4)
  - Fort Owen (Box 20, Folder 5)
  - Fort Pease (Box 20, Folder 6)
  - Fort Raymond (Box 20, Folder 7)
  - Fort Union (Box 20, Folder 8)
  - Fossils (Box 20, Folder 9)
  - French in Montana (Box 20, Folder 10)
  - Frontier Scout, 1864 July 14 (Box 20, Folder 11)
  - Fur Trade (Box 20, Folder 12)
  - Gallatin Range (West) (Box 20, Folder 13)
  - Gass, Patrick (Box 20, Folder 14)
  - Gazetter and Catalog (Box 20, Folder 15)
  - Geology (Box 20, Folder 16)
  - German Singing Societies (Box 20, Folder 17)
  - Ghost Towns / Castle (Box 20, Folder 18)
  - Gold (Box 20, Folder 19)
  - Governors of Montana (Box 20, Folder 20)
  - Graham, Jane (book dealer) (Box 20, Folder 21)
  - Granite Mining Company (Box 20, Folder 22)
  - Grant, John (Box 20, Folder 23)
  - Great Overland Stage Route (Box 20, Folder 24)
  - Plains Talk and Great Plains Newsletter (Box 20, Folder 25)
  - Guns (Box 20, Folder 26)
  - Guthrie, A.B. (Box 20, Folder 27)
  - Hangings (Box 20, Folder 28)
  - Havre (Box 20, Folder 29)
  - Harvard Research (Box 20, Folder 30)
  - Hedges, Cornelius (Box 20, Folder 31)
  - Hill Foundation (Box 20, Folder 32)
  - History of Montana Writing (Box 20, Folder 33)
  - Horse Capture, George P. (Box 20, Folder 34)
  - Hot Springs (Box 20, Folder 35)
  - Hudson's Bay Company (Box 20, Folder 36)
  - Hughes, Barney (Box 20, Folder 37)
  - Hutterites (Box 20, Folder 38)
  - Idaho (Box 20, Folder 39)
  - Indian Whiskey (Box 21, Folder 1)
  - Influence of the Military in the Building of Montana (Box 21, Folder 2)
  - Initial Point of Montana (Box 21, Folder 3)
  - Initiatives and referendums of Montana, 1908-1939 (Box 21, Folder 4)
  - Inland Empire (Box 21, Folder 5)
  - Interviews (Box 21, Folder 6)
  - Isolationists (Box 21, Folder 7)
  - Kinney, J.L. and Rhoten, Thomas (Box 21, Folder 8)
  - Koreans in Montana (Box 21, Folder 9)
  - Land Grant College (Box 21, Folder 10)
  - Land Ownership (Box 21, Folder 11)
  - Land Surveys (Box 21, Folder 12)
  - Larrabee, C.X. (Box 21, Folder 13)
  - "Last Buffalo of the Black Hills" (Box 21, Folder 14)
  - Frank Thomson (Box 21, Folder 15)
  - Legislature (Montana) (Box 21, Folder 16)
  - Library of Congress (Box 21, Folder 17)
  - Lichens (Box 21, Folder 18)
  - Literature (Box 21, Folder 19)
  - Lewis and Clark (Box 21, Folder 20)
  - Lewis and Clark (Box 21, Folder 21)
  - Lewis and Clark Caverns (Box 22, Folder 1)
  - Luther, Montana school alumni (Box 22, Folder 2)
  - Mackenzie River (Box 22, Folder 3)
  - Magazine articles and notes about Mt and West (Box 22, Folder 4)
  - Mageeisms (Box 22, Folder 5)
  - Makers of Montana (Box 22, Folder 6)
  - Manitoba Archives (Box 22, Folder 7)
  - Maps and decisions on geographic names in the U.S. (Box 22, Folder 8)
  - Maps (Montana) (Box 22, Folder 9)
  - "Market and Trade Center Patterns in Central Montana" (Box 22, Folder 10)
  - Masons (Montana) (Box 22, Folder 11)
  - Menard (Box 22, Folder 12)
  - Methodist Education (Box 22, Folder 13)
  - Military (Box 22, Folder 14)
  - Minerals (Box 22, Folder 15)
  - "The Mining Frontier in Montana" (Box 22, Folder 16)
  - Mission Mountains (Box 22, Folder 17)
  - Mission Valley (Box 22, Folder 18)
  - Missouri Breaks Woodchoppers (Box 22, Folder 19)
  - Missouri Historical Society (Box 22, Folder 20)
  - Montana (Box 22, Folder 21)
  - "Montana" (state song) (Box 22, Folder 22)
  - Montana Academy of Sciences (Box 22, Folder 23)
  - Montana Books (Box 22, Folder 24)
  - Montana Centennial (Box 22, Folder 25)
  - Montana Company Limited (Drum Lummon Mine) (Box 22, Folder 26)
  - Montana Constitution (Box 22, Folder 27)
  - Montana Education (Box 22, Folder 28)
  - "The Montana Face" Leslie Fiedler (Box 22, Folder 29)
  - Montana facts and figures (Box 22, Folder 30)
  - Montana Farmer's Federation (Box 22, Folder 31)
  - "Montana's First Airplane Flight" (Box 22, Folder 32)
  - "Twenty Years of 4-H Club Work in Montana" (Box 22, Folder 33)
  - "Montana Frontier" Merrill G. Burlingame (Box 22, Folder 34)
  - "Montana: A Geological Textbook" Maurice Holliday (Box 22, Folder 35)
  - Montana historic sites (Box 22, Folder 36)
  - Montana historical calendar (Box 22, Folder 37)
  - Montana history (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - Montana newspapers (Box 23, Folder 2)
  - "Montana the Magazine of Western History" (Box 23, Folder 3)
  - Montana Personality (Box 23, Folder 4)
  - Montana Politics (Box 23, Folder 5)
  - Montana Politics (Box 23, Folder 6)
  - Montana Power Company vs. Federal Power Commission (Box 23, Folder 7)
  - Speeches (Box 23, Folder 8)
  - Montana State Parks (Box 23, Folder 9)
  - Montana Tax Laws (Box 23, Folder 10)
  - "National Archives Microfilm Publications State Department Territorial Papers Montana---1864-1872" (Box 23, Folder 11)
  - Montana Wesleyan University (Box 23, Folder 12)
  - Montana Wildlands Coalition (Box 23, Folder 13)
  - Montana Writers (Box 23, Folder 14)
  - Montana/Wyoming Foundations (Box 23, Folder 15)
  - "The Northern Pacific Railroad and Montana's Mineral Lands" Thomas A. Clinch (Box 23, Folder 16)
  - Monuments and Statues (Box 23, Folder 17)
  - Mormons (Box 23, Folder 18)
  - Mouat Cliff Burials (Box 23, Folder 19)
  - Natural resources (historical development (Box 24, Folder 1)
  - National Archives-Seattle branch (Box 24, Folder 2)
  - Negroes in Montana (Box 24, Folder 3)
  - Sidwell vs. New Mine Sapphire Syndicate (Box 24, Folder 4)
  - New York Public Library (Box 24, Folder 5)
  - Northern Plains Bison Kills by Merrill G. Burlingame (Box 24, Folder 6)
  - Norris, Governor Edwin L. Message to 12th Legislative (Box 24, Folder 7)
  - Villard, Henry (Box 24, Folder 8)
  - Northwest History Syllabus (Box 24, Folder 9)
  - Notes (Box 24, Folder 10)
  - "The Future of Montana" O'Connor, George W. (Box 24, Folder 11)
  - Paleontology (Box 24, Folder 12)
  - Page family "Tell It Like It Was" Don Redfield (Box 24, Folder 13)
  - Parker, Reverend Samuel (Box 24, Folder 14)
  - Patten, Frances Smith (Box 24, Folder 15)
  - Personal books of Merrill G. Burlingame (Box 24, Folder 16)
  - Peyote (Box 24, Folder 17)
  - Photography in archeology (Box 24, Folder 18)
  - Picture (Montana's oldest) (Box 24, Folder 19)
  - Picture indexing (Box 24, Folder 20)
  - Poetry and prose (Box 24, Folder 21)
  - Politics (Box 24, Folder 22)
  - Population Patterns (Box 24, Folder 23)
  - Postal research (Box 24, Folder 24)
  - "Prehistoric Man in the Yellowstone Valley" S.W. Conner (Box 24, Folder 25)
  - Progressive movements (Box 24, Folder 26)
  - Public lands (Box 24, Folder 27)
  - Publication catalogs (Box 24, Folder 28)
  - Railroads (Box 24, Folder 29)
  - Ralston, J.K. (discussion) (Box 24, Folder 30)
  - Reader's Encyclopedia of the American West (Box 24, Folder 31)
  - Recipes (Box 24, Folder 32)
  - Red Bluff (James H. Bradley Memorial Summer Fellowship) Dr. Jeffrey Safford (Box 24, Folder 33)
  - Remington, Frederic (Box 24, Folder 34)
  - Rendezvous (Box 24, Folder 35)
  - Resources (Montana) (Box 24, Folder 36)
  - Ringling Circus (Box 25, Folder 1)
  - Rockefeller Foundation (Box 25, Folder 2)
  - Rock monuments or stone cairns (Box 25, Folder 3)
  - Rocky Mountain Laboratory (Box 25, Folder 4)
  - Roe, Martha Ann Freeman (transcript of diary) (Box 25, Folder 5)
  - Robison Rockshelter (Box 25, Folder 6)
  - Roosevelt, Theodore (Hunting trip to Gallatin), 1886 (Box 25, Folder 7)
  - Rosebud Expedition, 1874 (Box 25, Folder 8)
  - Rural Developments in Montana (Box 25, Folder 9)
  - Russell, C.M. (Box 25, Folder 10)
  - Saengerfest (Box 25, Folder 11)
  - "Saga of the Sage" Elmer Starch (Box 25, Folder 12)
  - St. Regis, Montana (Box 25, Folder 13)
  - Sanders, Sarepta (Box 25, Folder 14)
  - Saskatchewan (Box 25, Folder 15)
  - School lands (Montana) (Box 25, Folder 16)
  - Seward's Manifest Destiny, 1860 (Box 25, Folder 17)
  - Sheep (Box 25, Folder 18)
  - Sheepeater (Box 25, Folder 19)
  - Sipes, Lawson J. (Box 25, Folder 20)
  - Smallpox (Box 25, Folder 21)
  - Smith, Governor Green Clay (Box 25, Folder 22)
  - Socialist Party and Newspapers (Box 25, Folder 23)
  - "Social Security in a Frontier Mining Camp" (Box 25, Folder 24)
  - Songs of miners in Butte, Montana (Box 25, Folder 25)
  - Sources (Box 25, Folder 26)
  - South Dakota maps (Box 25, Folder 27)
  - Spanish in early Montana (Box 25, Folder 28)
  - Speech materials (Box 25, Folder 29)
  - Speer, J.B. (University of Montana) (Box 25, Folder 30)
  - Stage Route (Bozeman to Helena) (Box 25, Folder 31)
  - Statehood (Montana) (Box 25, Folder 32)
  - Station names (Montana) (Box 25, Folder 33)
  - Steamboats (Box 25, Folder 34)
  - St. Vincent's Academy (Box 25, Folder 35)
  - Supreme Court (Montana) (Box 25, Folder 36)
  - Survival certificate (Box 25, Folder 37)
  - Sutherlin, Robert (Box 25, Folder 38)
  - Telephone and telegraph (Box 25, Folder 39)
  - Television project (Montana) (Box 25, Folder 40)
  - Territorial warrant (Montana) (Box 26, Folder 1)
  - Thanksgiving (Box 26, Folder 2)
  - Theses bibliography, 1942 (Box 26, Folder 3)
  - Third parties in Montana (Box 26, Folder 4)
  - Toll roads (Box 26, Folder 5)
  - Toole, K. Ross (Box 26, Folder 6)
  - Tours and trivia (Box 26, Folder 7)
  - Trading posts (Box 26, Folder 8)
  - Transportation (Box 26, Folder 9)
  - Tulane (Box 26, Folder 10)
  - Turkeys (Box 26, Folder 11)
  - "The Turner Thesis: A Problem in Historiography" (Box 26, Folder 12)
  - Twain, Mark (Box 26, Folder 13)
  - "Unidentified White Men in Western Montana in and about 1810" S.W. Conner (Box 26, Folder 14)
  - U.S. Army transcripts (Box 26, Folder 15)
  - U.S. Army transcripts (Box 26, Folder 16)
  - U.S. - Canada boundary treaty centennial, 1946 (Box 26, Folder 17)
  - University of North Carolina collections (Box 26, Folder 18)
  - Verendrye, C. and L. (Box 26, Folder 19)
  - Victor, Montana (Box 26, Folder 20)
  - Vigilantes (Box 26, Folder 21)
  - Vigilantes (Box 26, Folder 22)
  - Vigilantes (Box 27, Folder 1)
  - Vigilantes (Box 27, Folder 2)
  - Virginia City/Bannock Stage Route (Box 27, Folder 3)
  - Virginia City Players (Box 27, Folder 4)
  - Wagon trips to Yellowstone (Box 27, Folder 5)
  - Water rights and water courts (Box 27, Folder 6)
  - Watson, Helena (Box 27, Folder 7)
  - Watson, William H. - weather (Box 27, Folder 8)
  - "The American West, Perpetual Mirage" (Box 27, Folder 9)
  - "Westering Man, the Life of Joseph Walker" (Box 27, Folder 10)
  - White, Thain, "Artifacts from the Battle of the Rosebud" (Box 27, Folder 11)
  - Whoop-Up Trail (Box 27, Folder 12)
  - Wigwam Creek Tipis (Box 27, Folder 13)
  - Wild Flowers and Shrubs of Montana (Box 27, Folder 14)
  - Winter 1862-1863 Montana residents (Box 27, Folder 15)
  - Winter, 1886-1887 (Box 27, Folder 16)
  - Women in Montana (Box 27, Folder 17)
  - Worthen, C.B. (Box 27, Folder 18)
  - WPA Archeological projects (Box 27, Folder 19)
  - Yale (Box 27, Folder 20)
  - Yellowstone Expedition, 1874-1876 (Box 27, Folder 21)
  - Yellowstone Institute (Box 27, Folder 22)
  - Yellowstone National Park (Box 27, Folder 23)
  - Yellowstone River Valley (Box 27, Folder 24)
- General correspondences, 4
  Letters written to or by Merrill Burlingame on a wide variety of research topics and matters of personal interest. Unlike correspondence found in the other series, these letters were maintained by Burlingame as a separate file regardless of their subject content. As a result much of the information contained within the letters pertains to subject files listed elsewhere. Most files are quite scant, containing few reference queries or brief replies from Burlingame. An important exception are the letters of W. J. "Duke" Ellington, an employee of the U.S. Bureau of Indian Affairs and administrator at the Rocky Boy reservation in the 1940s. The folders have been alphabetically arranged by the title Burlingame assigned them.
  - Alderson, Angela (Box 28, Folder 1)
  - Annin, Jim (Box 28, Folder 2)
  - Aubrey, J.S. (Box 28, Folder 3)
  - Baldwin, Henry T. (Box 28, Folder 4)
  - Ballard, Jack A. (Box 28, Folder 5)
  - Balzhiser, Tom (Box 28, Folder 6)
  - Barbour, Philip R. (Box 28, Folder 7)
  - Bartlett, W.A. (Box 28, Folder 8)
  - Bess, Glenn R. (Box 28, Folder 9)
  - Binfords and Mort Publishers (Box 28, Folder 10)
  - Blackmore, William (Box 28, Folder 11)
  - Bovey, Charles (Box 28, Folder 12)
  - Bowen, K. (Box 28, Folder 13)
  - Bowen, Marie (Box 28, Folder 14)
  - Bradley, Charles and Nina (Box 28, Folder 15)
  - Brankeman, W.J. (Box 28, Folder 16)
  - Brown, Mark H. (Box 28, Folder 17)
  - Brownell, Baker (Box 28, Folder 18)
  - Burlingame Christmas letter (Box 28, Folder 19)
  - Call, Hughie (Box 28, Folder 19A)
  - Callaway, L.L. (Box 28, Folder 20)
  - Campbell, Mike (Box 28, Folder 21)
  - Cannon, Irene (Box 28, Folder 22)
  - Chappel, Charles (Box 28, Folder 23)
  - Clack, Elinor (Box 28, Folder 24)
  - Clark, Wm. Andrews Memorial Library (Box 28, Folder 25)
  - Coe, Auburn (Box 28, Folder 26)
  - Coe, William R. (Box 28, Folder 27)
  - Combes, Geneva (Box 28, Folder 28)
  - Comfort, John C. (Box 28, Folder 29)
  - Conner, S.W. (Box 28, Folder 30)
  - Cooper, Myrtle (Box 28, Folder 31)
  - Counter, Janice (Box 28, Folder 32)
  - Cushman, Margaret (Box 28, Folder 33)
  - Czura, Pete (Box 28, Folder 34)
  - Davidson, V.G. (Box 28, Folder 35)
  - Davis, Les (Box 28, Folder 36)
  - Dean, Mayo Story (Box 28, Folder 37)
  - Demarest, Mrs. Claude (Box 28, Folder 38)
  - Doig, Ivan (Box 28, Folder 39)
  - Downing, Warwick (Box 28, Folder 40)
  - Duboc, Jesse (Box 28, Folder 41)
  - Ellingsen, John D. (Box 28, Folder 42)
  - Ewers, John C. (Box 28, Folder 43)
  - Floerchinger, Dorothy (Box 28, Folder 44)
  - Gerard, Howard (Box 28, Folder 45)
  - Gardiner, Dorothy (Box 28, Folder 46)
  - Gill, Larry (Box 28, Folder 47)
  - Graham, Edith L. (Box 28, Folder 48)
  - Graham, Jessica (Box 28, Folder 49)
  - Grant, Marilyn (Box 28, Folder 50)
  - Graves, Lee (Box 28, Folder 51)
  - Haines, Aubrey (Box 28, Folder 52)
  - Griffin, Harvey and Vida (Box 28, Folder 53)
  - Hammond, G.P. (Box 28, Folder 54)
  - Hansen, Grace (Box 28, Folder 55)
  - Hart, A.L. (Box 28, Folder 56)
  - Hasner, Sharon (Box 28, Folder 57)
  - Heath, John L. (Box 28, Folder 58)
  - Heidel, Charles (Box 28, Folder 59)
  - Holter, Mary (Box 28, Folder 60)
  - Huffman, Roy (Box 28, Folder 61)
  - Hutchins, James S. (Box 28, Folder 62)
  - Ireland, Elizabeth (Box 28, Folder 63)
  - Jasmann, Alice O. (Box 28, Folder 64)
  - Jones, Jefferson (Box 28, Folder 65)
  - Judge, Governor Thomas (Box 28, Folder 66)
  - Kaschube, Dorothea (Box 28, Folder 67)
  - Koch, Elers (Box 28, Folder 68)
  - Koury, Michael J. (Box 28, Folder 69)
  - Kroes, Rob (Box 28, Folder 70)
  - Larsen, W.E. (Box 28, Folder 71)
  - Leggat Collection (Box 28, Folder 72)